

FULL STACK DEVELOPER



(916) 540-9352



Billy.Todd50@outlook.com



linkedin.com/BillyTodd



BillyTodd.com

## **TECHNOLOGIES**

## **FRONT END:**

HTML5 CSS3 **JAVASCRIPT JQUERY BOOTSTRAP REACT & REDUX** 

## **BACK END:**

NODE **EXPRESS** MONGODB **MONGOOSE PASSPORT** RESTFUL API

#### OTHER:

GIT **GITHUB JEST** 

## **SOFT SKILLS**

**Effective Communication** 

**Excellent Interpersonal Skills** 

Teamwork

Progress Driven

Self-Motivated

**Problem Solving** 

Grow in the Job

Adaptibility

## PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Detail-oriented professional with five years of experience with inside sales and project management. Quickly adapting to new technologies and platforms to accomplish the job. Excel in team environments with strong interpersonal skills. Excellent written and oral communication skills; capable of explaining complex issues in easy-to-understand terms. I'm using my strengths and skills to aid in my passion for Web Development.

# LATEST PROJECTS

#### YELPCAMP

HTML & CSS / Node, Express & MongoDB / Mongoose & Passport A Camp Sharing Website using RESTful services while incorporating CRUD with the Campsites and their comments.

Visit Project: <u>YelpCamp.herokuapp.com</u>

#### AHOUSE REAL ESTATE

HTML & CSS / Node & Express / Bootstrap A modern take on a Real Esate Agency site using Bootstrap.

Visit Project: <u>AHouseRealEstate.herokuapp.com</u>

#### **ROBOFRIENDS**

React & Redux / Webpack / JSX & CSS / PWA / Jest

A Progressive Web Application using React and Redux. Made with Create-React-App that implemented reducers.

Visit Project: Robofriends.github.io





Roseville, CA







FULL STACK DEVELOPER

## OTHER SKILLS

Typing speed of 70 WPM

**Pubic Speaking Proficiency** 

Risk Management

Creativity

## **EDUCATION**

Heald College Roseville, CA

Attended: 07/2011-01/2013 IT Network Security Program

Sierra College Rocklin, CA

Attended: 08/2013-12/2013 Enrolled courses: Algebra 2 AutoCAD 101 Architecture 101



Psychology

### REFERENCES

Available Upon Request

### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **QUOTATIONS / INSIDE SALES**

CAL Lighting I Rancho Cordova, CA, USA I 04/2017 – 04/2019

- Controlled Central Coast and Northern Nevada territory. Through building relationships and networking, I grew my territories to produce over \$300K in net profit.
- Communicated efficiently with Sales and managing Principal's to meet and exceed deadlines with competitive prices. Executing 50 Bids a week.
- Maintained extensive knowledge of competitors offerings and presence in assigned territories. Allowing me to advocate Sales force effectively. Providing price advantages of 5-20% on outgoing bids.

### **QUOTATIONS / INSIDE SALES**

Ewing Foley Inc. I *Auburn, CA, USA* I **08/2016 – 04/2017** 

- Attended weekly meetings to communicate and inform all Sales force of incoming and potential projects. Raising awareness resulted in 10% increase of project acquisition.
- Handled quotes inbox of all incoming requests, delegating out to the correct personnel to free up the team to focus on their own work. Routed roughly 200 emails a day excluding my own.
- Acquired new business by providing Value Engineered jobs that met the end user's requirements while saving them money. Resulting in a dozen projects awarded over \$50K in value.

#### **QUOTATIONS / PROJECT MANAGER**

Graybar Electric Co. I Sacramento, CA, USA I 04/2014 - 08/2016

- Managed up to 20 projects at a time. Fulfilling all needs of the Contractor's to ensure project was as smooth as possible. Resulting in me being asked to manage more projects by satisfied Contractor's.
- Provided Operation's and Maintenance manuals for all project's to the end user. My most notable project was the Sacramento King's Arena which totaled about 1900 pages.
- Implemented Color coding on status reports, making them visually easier to read and determine if product has been ordered, shipped or when it will be shipped. Saving time, helping to significantly reduce clerical errors and ensure the job is 100% completed.